Guide to the Aerie collection ARCH164
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
Aerie collection
1996-2019
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
ARCH164
0.83 Linear Feet (2 containers)
A collection of the University of Hartford's literary journal, Aerie from 1996 - 2017.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to all researchers.
Historical Note
Named after the nest of a hawk, Aerie, was first published in November 1996 by the University of Hartford's English Department as a student writing magazine created from submissions to the department's writing competition in the Spring of 1996. The second volume was not published until the spring of 1998. Aerie has been published in the spring ever since.
Over the years there have been several problems with the volume numbers. The volumes that were published in 2005 and 2006 are both called volume 5. There is no volume 15 as the numbers jumped from volume 14 in 2011 to volume 16 in 2012. Volume 18 is used for both the 2014 and 2015 issues. Volumes 19 and 20 also do not exist as the numbers jump from volume 18 in 2015 to volume 21 in 2016. This may have been an attempt to correct previous mistakes, as it would have been the 21st volume had Aerie been published every year since 1996; however, there was no issue in 1997.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains every issue of the University of Hartford's English Department magazine of student writing, Aerie from 1996 - 2017. The collection also contains a few notices pertaining to submission guidelines.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by filename.
Periodicals; Student publications; University of Hartford. Department of English and Modern Languages
- Issues, 1996 - 2019
  - Vol. 1, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Vol. 2, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Vol. 3, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Vol. 4, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Vol. 5, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Vol. 5, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Vol. 6, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Vol. 7, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Vol. 8, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Vol. 9, 2006 (Box 1)
  - Vol. 10, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Vol. 11, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Vol. 12, 2009 (Box 1)
  - Vol. 13, 2010 (Box 1)
  - Vol. 14, 2011 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 16, 2012 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 17, 2013 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 18, 2014 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 18, 2015 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 21, 2016 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 22, 2017 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 23, 2018; 3 Volumes (Box 2)
  - Vol. 24, 2019; 2 Volumes Duplicates (Box 2)
- Submission Guidelines, 2008; 2015; undated (Box 2)